# ADAM BOKON

20 Rose Lane • Shannock, RI 02875

Mobile: +1-617-817-2773 • Email: adam.bokon@fuqua.duke.edu
Nationality: American • Languages: English

#### **OBJECTIVE**

As a recent MBA graduate with US and international academic experience, I am seeking an opportunity in commercial real estate. I can leverage my 7 years of real estate finance and underwriting experience, sales and relationship management training, educational learnings and strong interpersonal skills to contribute to the organization in a positive and meaningful manner.

### **EDUCATION**

MBA, University of New South Wales, Australian Graduate School of Management (AGSM)

Sydney, Australia

Master of Business Administration

1/2010 - 8/2011

Coursework Includes: Finance; Strategies for Growth; Integrated Marketing Communications;

ne.

Strategic Management Project: Table4Ten organization

- Duke University, The Fugua School of Business - Academic Exchange

**Durham, NC** 1/2011 – 5/2011

GPA: 3.50

Coursework Includes:

Venture Capital and Private Equity; Energy, Markets & Innovation;

Product Development; Medical Device Commercialization

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration, University of Connecticut

Storrs, CT

GPA: 3.48 (Overall); 3.63 (Business School); 4.00 (Real Estate Program)

9/1999 - 5/2003

Major: Finance / Real Estate • Cum Laude

Coursework Includes: Real Estate Decision Making; Real Estate Investments; Real Estate Finance

- University College Dublin, Quinn School of Business - Academic Exchange

Dublin, Ireland 9/2001 – 12/2001

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

People's United Bank

Hartford, CT

Commercial Real Estate Loan Officer – Assistant Vice President

4/2006 - 1/2010

Responsibility included overseeing the origination, underwriting and closing of new commercial real estate lending opportunities. Routinely reviewed property leasing, appraisals and negotiated the loan structures/terms between investors and banking management. Underwriting and financial analysis included due diligence of NOI, DCF's, IRR, ROI and quality of model forecasting assumptions.

- Closed an average of US\$15M in financing annually, with approximately 75% resulting from new business sourced through networking and referral channels and 25% resulting from the continued fostering of established client relationships
- Managed a US\$50M+ portfolio of performing commercial real estate credits by coordinating the activities of supporting team members (direct & indirect reports)
- Developed plan of actions for troubled loans to avert workout and default for senior management and borrowers
- Provided solutions for investors of large retail, office, hospitality, industrial, multi-family and residential construction properties

Wachovia Bank Hartford, CT

Business Banking Relationship Manager (Mid-Market Commercial, Industrial and Real Estate Lending)

6/2003 - 3/2006

- Conducted financial analysis and established new relationships with businesses that had annual revenues of US\$3-15M
- Participated in an 18-month Business Banking Associate rotational program that provided additional exposure and training in retail/commercial banking, wealth management and asset-based lending functions
- Completed the intensive Wachovia Credit Training Program in Charlotte, North Carolina (corporate headquarters)

#### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

# The Mutual Housing Association of Greater Hartford

**Board of Directors** 

Hartford, CT 9/2007 – 12/2009

Responsibility included leveraging my industry experience to influence the direction of the area's largest affordable housing organization (10 properties, 500+ units) while serving the mission of revitalizing the neighborhoods of greater Hartford.

- Appointed and elected to oversee a period of significant growth that included several multi-unit apartment acquisitions through the use of tax credits (LIHTC) and grants as well as an expansion into the property management business
- Directly involved with organization's year-long strategic planning initiative to shape future 3-5 year growth
- Represented their interests from local gatherings with residents to national conferences in Chicago and Washington D.C.

## **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

- Software Skills: Argus, Excel, PowerPoint, Windows XP/Vista, Mac OS X & financial modeling applications
- AGSM Alumni Management Project Prize, 2011
- AGSM Sports and Management Club President, 2010
- Easter Seals of Greater Hartford Rehabilitation Centre Committee Member, 2006-2009
- Real Estate Finance Association (REFA) Member, 2006-2009
- 1st degree black belt in traditional Shorinryu karate
- Interests include reading, golf, fitness, skiing, scuba diving, traveling, investing and my playful yellow Labrador rescue. Sheila